<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Pushin&#039; &#38; pullin&#039; pixels on the net &#187; Podcast Feed</title>
	<atom:link href="https://pixelhandler.dev/?feed=podcast" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://pixelhandler.dev</link>
	<description>Internet Broadcast : Pushing Text and Pixels on the Net</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 20:53:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<copyright>2008-2010 </copyright>
	<managingEditor>no-reply@pixelhandler.dev (Bill Heaton)</managingEditor>
	<webMaster>no-reply@pixelhandler.dev (Bill Heaton)</webMaster>
	<ttl>1440</ttl>
	<image>
		<url>https://pixelhandler.dev/images/Pixelhandler-art-sm.jpg</url>
		<title>Pushin&#039; &amp; pullin&#039; pixels on the net &#187; Podcast Feed</title>
		<link>https://pixelhandler.dev</link>
		<width>144</width>
		<height>144</height>
	</image>
	<itunes:subtitle>pixelhander.com</itunes:subtitle>
	<itunes:summary>Internet Broadcast : Pushing Text and Pixels on the Net</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:keywords>internet marketing, web design, web development, search engine optimization, search engine marketing, SEO, SEM</itunes:keywords>
	<itunes:category text="Technology" />
	<itunes:author>Bill Heaton</itunes:author>
	<itunes:owner>
		<itunes:name>Bill Heaton</itunes:name>
		<itunes:email>no-reply@pixelhandler.dev</itunes:email>
	</itunes:owner>
	<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
	<itunes:image href="https://pixelhandler.dev/images/Pixelhandler-art.jpg" />
		<item>
		<title>Winning the #1 Search Engine Result for Your Key Phrase</title>
		<link>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/search-engine-result-number-one-for-your-key-phrase</link>
		<comments>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/search-engine-result-number-one-for-your-key-phrase#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2008 21:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bill Heaton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engine optimization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engine results pages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search query]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SERPs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Design]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pixelhandler.dev/?p=88</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Internet Marketing Report and Social Media Highlights Newsletter &#8211; July 2008 This newsletter will mail out the first week of each month, please visit the link below to opt-in http://lists.pixelhandler.dev &#8216;Bill&#8217;s Internet Marketing Report&#8217; - Winning the #1 Search Engine Result for Your Key Phrase -&#160; Strategies and topics relating to the happenings I experience in the race of marketing, publishing and selling on the web. Having the top result on Google for your main key phrase  <a class="more" href="https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/search-engine-result-number-one-for-your-key-phrase">
	&#187;&#160;Read&#160;more&#160;&#8230;</a>]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/search-engine-result-number-one-for-your-key-phrase/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="https://pixelhandler.dev/podpress_trac/feed/88/0/winning-search-engine-result-number-one.mp3" length="7243946" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:07:30</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Internet Marketing Report and Social Media Highlights Newsletter &#8211; July 2008
This newsletter will mail out the first week of each month, please visit the link below to opt-in http://lists.pixelhandler.dev
&#8216;Bill&#8217;s Internet Marketing[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Internet Marketing Report and Social Media Highlights Newsletter &#8211; July 2008
This newsletter will mail out the first week of each month, please visit the link below to opt-in http://lists.pixelhandler.dev
&#8216;Bill&#8217;s Internet Marketing Report&#8217; - Winning the #1 Search Engine Result for Your Key Phrase
-&#160; Strategies and topics relating to the happenings I experience in the race of marketing, publishing and selling on the web.
Having the top result on Google for your main key phrase just feels great! Seriously, in this time of uncertainty, being number one even for a short time is pretty cool. It is also nice when a competitor enters the market and previously held the #1 search result which you now hold.
Search engine optimization : the search query is : noninvasive neuromodulation

We&#8217;re number one! Results 1 &#8211; 10 of about 92,500 for noninvasive neuromodulation. 
Mid month the decision is made to update the web site with new terminology
Take a vacation and violá the search crawler does it&#8217;s magic and the result is favorable
the competitor who previously ranked #1 for the search query was bumped down but still on page one of Google

Recent changes in Google&#8217;s search engine results pages (SERPs) for google account holders:

While logged in to google the SERPs vary based on the same search query
Fresh/new content ranks higher then seems to drop as newer posts assume the search query&#8217;s freshness
Holding the #1 ranking in the SERP will required continued link building, hence this post!

Sites referenced:

google.com
vqorthocare.com
  

&#8216;Highlights in Social Media&#8217; - Online Networks for Web Designers and Developers
- The Internet is bringing people together and making connections for personal and professional development. Being involved socially online is a way to build new relationships with like-minded individuals.
Last month I created a Ning network, at refreshoc.ning.com, and as a results was invited to join dezumo.com ; there I joined the conversations on web design and posted a forum topic &#34;What are your favorite sites for inspiration on the topic of Web design?&#34; Dezumo has about 293 members and has been around for about a year while the RefreshOC started a month ago and only has about 18 members. Dezumo is has a larger audience while RefreshOC is targeting a local metro area. Both were kicked off right here in Orange County. I enjoy the conversations on dezumo and am hoping the RefreshOC group will become more active as social networks become more of a source for making connections locally.
On the subject of inspiration for web design I did receive a few responses from the group, I visited the links and found some fresh sites to add to my del.icio.us bookmarks on the topic of design . While a couple people were eager to share links for inspiration sake one designer posted a note to creating new design without being tempted to follow the pack; along with this response were no links but a tip on seeking inspiration from the world around you. I am very fond of this concept of being inspired from life itself, but also find it very valuable to examine successful design concepts. Design techniques that work well should be mimicked, especially for the sake of user experience and usability.

Sites referenced: 

refreshoc.com
dezumo.com
del.icio.us



Found on the PodSafeMusicNetwork: 
Listen the track titled, The Pain Of Numbers by Get Three Coffins Ready &#8211; at the end of the broadcast!</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Marketing, Search, Social</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bill Heaton</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reasons for Business Blogging and Kicking Off a Local Socal Network</title>
		<link>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/business-blogging-local-socal-network</link>
		<comments>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/business-blogging-local-socal-network#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 18:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bill Heaton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://2019542286</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Internet Marketing Report and Social Media Highlights Newsletter &#8211; June 2008 This newsletter will mail out the first week of each month, please visit the link below to opt-in http://lists.pixelhandler.dev &#8216;Bill&#8217;s Internet Marketing Report&#8217; - Another good reason for businesses to blog -&#160; Strategies and topics relating to the happenings I experience in the race of marketing, publishing and selling on the web. I&#8217;m currently employed by a medical equipment manufacturer and distributor (I freelance too) and  <a class="more" href="https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/business-blogging-local-socal-network">
	&#187;&#160;Read&#160;more&#160;&#8230;</a>]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/business-blogging-local-socal-network/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="https://pixelhandler.dev/podpress_trac/feed/77/0/Business-Blog-Local-Socal-Network.mp3" length="10218251" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:10:36</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Internet Marketing Report and Social Media Highlights Newsletter &#8211; June 2008 
This newsletter will mail out the first week of each month, please visit the link below to opt-in http://lists.pixelhandler.dev
&#8216;Bill&#8217;s Internet Marketin[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Internet Marketing Report and Social Media Highlights Newsletter &#8211; June 2008 
This newsletter will mail out the first week of each month, please visit the link below to opt-in http://lists.pixelhandler.dev
&#8216;Bill&#8217;s Internet Marketing Report&#8217; - Another good reason for businesses to blog
-&#160; Strategies and topics relating to the happenings I experience in the race of marketing, publishing and selling on the web.
I&#8217;m currently employed by a medical equipment manufacturer and distributor (I freelance too) and last month some very interesting news was broadcast on news radio and the internet about the LA Laker&#8217;s own Kobe Bryant and his back injury.

From latimes.com &#8212; May 13, 2008 
		&#34;I tried to play and make drives to the basket where I could kind of withstand the pain without the back completely spasming and then put the next game really in jeopardy,&#34; Bryant said.
On Monday he addressed reporters while standing, as he did during Sunday&#8217;s postgame news conference. Bryant said he would receive round-the-clock treatment.
His regimen includes ice, heat, massage and stretching. Bryant also held his electrical stimulation device by his side, saying he would basically sleep with it the next couple days.

The reason why this news was inspiring for my employer is that the company&#8217;s main product offering does just what Kobe&#8217;s medical device does and more. This news became a great way for the company to share with clients about just how good their technology really is; also sharing the story about Kobe saying &#8220;he would basically sleep with it the next couple days.&#8221; In following up on the report, Kobe did not miss a game during this series and continued to score very well, while the Lakers moved on to the next playoff series. 
The reason why this news was so valuable to blog about is that it allowed the company&#8217;s news blog to add valuable content supporting the site&#8217;s search engine optimizations (SEO) objectives. The general public may use different variations of the words that a business uses to describe its offerings. The blog format allows for a very quick response to optimizing the companies Web site with the terms used by the general public and reporters.  The best benefit is that the reported did report on Kobe talking about a medical condition that my employee has a solution for, back spasms!
Once the blog was posted, the same day as multiple news agencies reported on the injury I sent off an email to a targeted group of clients that would be very impressed with the technology and hearing that a professional basketball player and NBA MVP says so. That perspective was a lot better than I could say, even though I used the technology after a broken leg and shoulder and loved how well the medical device blocked my pain. 
The return on investment for this blog and email blast was that conversation were opened up with key clients who needed to learn more about the technology and how it fit in within the sports profession.
Sites referenced:

http://www.latimes.com/sports/
http://www.vqorthocare.com/blog/
	

&#8216;Highlights in Social Media&#8217; - Starting up an online social network with NING
- The Internet is bringing people together and making connections for personal and professional development. Being involved socially online is a way to build new relationships with like-minded individuals.
Recently I became interested in social media and networking with other like minded Internet professionals. My favorite online social networks are linkedin.com and twitter.com, I use facebook.com and a few others less often. When I read about ning.com in FastCompany magazine and also heard about ning.com again during a local meetup in OC. This got my created juices flowing and since I enjoy networking with other professionals, and also have spent much of my career flying solo (as an in-house person or working from home), I was inspired to kick off a n[...]</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Marketing, Social</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bill Heaton</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Internet Marketing Report and Social Media Highlights Newsletter &#8211; May &#8217;08</title>
		<link>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/internet-marketing-report-and-social-media-highlights-newsletter-may-08</link>
		<comments>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/internet-marketing-report-and-social-media-highlights-newsletter-may-08#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2008 15:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bill Heaton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://2079207195</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Well, it&#8217;s about time! I finally committed myself to personal branding and sharing both professional topics and personal insights/news via an email newsletter. This mailing is managed by an online database for easy opt-in and out-out choices. I am sending you this message since we have been in contact either professionally or personally (friends and family included). This newsletter will mail out the first week of each month, please visit the link below to opt-in http://lists.pixelhandler.dev. Internet  <a class="more" href="https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/internet-marketing-report-and-social-media-highlights-newsletter-may-08">
	&#187;&#160;Read&#160;more&#160;&#8230;</a>]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/internet-marketing-report-and-social-media-highlights-newsletter-may-08/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="https://pixelhandler.dev/podpress_trac/feed/35/0/InternetMarketingReport-Newsletter-007.mp3" length="9335617" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:07:00</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Well, it&#8217;s about time! I finally committed myself to personal branding and sharing both professional topics and personal insights/news via an email newsletter. This mailing is managed by an online database for easy opt-in and out-out choices. [...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Well, it&#8217;s about time! I finally committed myself to personal branding and sharing both professional topics and personal insights/news via an email newsletter. This mailing is managed by an online database for easy opt-in and out-out choices. I am sending you this message since we have been in contact either professionally or personally (friends and family included).

This newsletter will mail out the first week of each month, please visit the link below to opt-in http://lists.pixelhandler.dev.


Internet Marketing Report and Social Media Highlights Newsletter&#8230;

&#8216;Bill&#8217;s Internet Marketing Report&#8217; 
-&#160; An ongoing theme in my newsletter. I will publish strategies and topics relating to the happenings I experience in the race of marketing, publishing and selling on the web.


This month&#8217;s topic is linkbait. One of the best ways to increase search engine optimization performance is improving your rankings by growing your list of inbound links to your Web site. This is one strategy that takes persistence and pays off over time. Without a strong link building strategy it can be very difficult to gain higher rankings in the search engine results pages (SERPs), especially for competitive keywords or search phrases. The goal is to be number one on the first page of your favorite search engine using a phase that is searched for very often by your desired audience. The linkbait that I am currently offering is a free website theme for bloggers.


This month I released downloadable file as blog theme for photo enthusiasts in order to gain more inbound links to my personal blog. My site is managed using WordPress, one of the most widely used open source Web applications for online publishing. The WordPress site has a large community with a high volume of online traffic, of which a large segment of users desire to customize their own blog with a custom design, free of charge!


Because I enjoy the benefit of the contributions made by this online community, I finally took the opportunity to give back, by offering Shoot It! a free photo blog theme. This professional web design should prove to be a favorite among photography enthusiasts and professionals alike. Within a couple days of uploading the Shoot It! theme to my blog, I noticed ten downloads have taken place. I believe the numbers will grow even faster once the theme is listed on the WordPress theme site.


As a demonstration site, I launched a pro photo tips blog, Take Better Photos Now, with content provided by a very seasoned photographer with a passion for sharing tips to help people take better photos. Michael Kitada plans to publish tips for photography enthusiasts and this will benefit his photography business as well by providing inbound traffic to his main Web site. His new blog using this photography theme already has about 100 unique visitors with the first couple weeks while creating the Web site design. I anticipate that the volume of links will be begin to grow from the promotion of this free offer and also from the links created by bloggers using the free theme.


Sites referenced: 
http://takebetterphotosnow.com 

&#8216;Highlights in Social Media&#8217; 
- Second theme with a focus on building your personal brand using online networking. The Internet is bringing people together and making connections for personal and professional development. Being involved socially online is a way to build new relationships with like-minded individuals.


Last month, my wife and I attended a meetup in Irvine on the topic of internet marketing. We both were able to learn new information and meet others involved in selling and promoting on the Internet. This came about by visiting meetup.com and searching for internet marketing. This is the second time that I have searched online with the intention of learning something new, then followed up by meeting a group of like-mined people (offline and in person) who share their knowledge openly among [...]</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>internet, marketing, web, design, web, development, search, engine, optimization, search, engine, marketing</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bill Heaton</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Answers for Internet Marketing, SEO, Business and Promotion</title>
		<link>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/answers-for-internet-marketing-seo-and-business</link>
		<comments>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/answers-for-internet-marketing-seo-and-business#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 05:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bill Heaton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[donations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[promotion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://2084574360</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week I spent some time getting social with LinkedIn.com I answered a few questions related to my profession. This episode (6) covers the questions in short form with links to the original questions with the linkedin community answers, you will need to log-in at linkedin.com to view the links in this post. The audio player above includes the additional explanations to these questions and comments on the answers submitted by the linkedin members. Also, I play a song titled, Finish What We Started, by Headway and can be found online at... http://www.podsafemusicnetwork.com]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/answers-for-internet-marketing-seo-and-business/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="https://pixelhandler.dev/podpress_trac/feed/11/0/Answers-Marketing-SEO-Pixelhandler006.mp3" length="15403531" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:16:00</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>This week I spent some time getting social with LinkedIn.com I answered a few questions related to my profession. This episode (6) covers the questions in short form with links to the original questions with the linkedin community answers, you will [...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>This week I spent some time getting social with LinkedIn.com I answered a few questions related to my profession. This episode (6) covers the questions in short form with links to the original questions with the linkedin community answers, you will need to log-in at linkedin.com to view the links in this post. The audio player above includes the additional explanations to these questions and comments on the answers submitted by the linkedin members. Also, I play a song titled, Finish What We Started, by Headway and can be found online at... http://www.podsafemusicnetwork.com</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Marketing, Search</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bill Heaton</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conversion Optimization by Strategic Design</title>
		<link>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/conversion-optimization</link>
		<comments>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/conversion-optimization#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2008 08:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bill Heaton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conversion Optimization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ROI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Design]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://356724192</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This 10 minute review highlights the key points in the book that helped me learn the process for conversion optimization – converting my site visitors into customers.]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/conversion-optimization/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="https://pixelhandler.dev/podpress_trac/feed/10/0/Review_WebDesign4ROI-Pixelhandler005.mp3" length="5109685" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:10:33</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Pixel Handler Radio : Episode 5</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>This 10 minute review highlights the key points in the book that helped me learn the process for conversion optimization – converting my site visitors into customers.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>internet, marketing, web, design, web, development, search, engine, optimization, search, engine, marketing</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bill Heaton</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Web Site/Domain Indexed by Google in only 3 Days from Launch</title>
		<link>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/new-web-sitedomain-indexed-by-google-in-3-days-from-launch</link>
		<comments>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/new-web-sitedomain-indexed-by-google-in-3-days-from-launch#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2007 22:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bill Heaton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indexed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web site]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pixelhandler.dev/?p=9</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A story based on a web site donated to the charity, Miracle Ranch Orphanage Foundation.]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/new-web-sitedomain-indexed-by-google-in-3-days-from-launch/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="https://pixelhandler.dev/podpress_trac/feed/9/0/Indexedin3Days-Pixelhandler004.mp3" length="16871990" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:22:15</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Pixel Handler Radio : Episode 4</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>A story based on a web site donated to the charity, Miracle Ranch Orphanage Foundation.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Marketing, Search</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bill Heaton</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twenty Questions to Plan Your Web Site Project</title>
		<link>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/web-project-questions</link>
		<comments>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/web-project-questions#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2007 09:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bill Heaton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unique selling proposition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web project]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://1816650168</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every Web project needs a solid plan to work through the estimate to the site delivery. Here is a list of project questions to plan your Web site with considerations for marketing, design, SEO, unique selling position, E-commerce, and more&#8230; How would you describe the audience you want to attract? Do you want the design to reflect your organization or your audience? What is the primary message you wish to convey to your audience with this project?  <a class="more" href="https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/web-project-questions">
	&#187;&#160;Read&#160;more&#160;&#8230;</a>]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/web-project-questions/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="https://pixelhandler.dev/podpress_trac/feed/8/0/TwentyProjectQuestions-Pixelhandler-3.mp3" length="5768155" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:08:03</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Every Web project needs a solid plan to work through the estimate to the site delivery. Here is a list of project questions to plan your Web site with considerations for marketing, design, SEO, unique selling position, E-commerce, and more&#8230;


[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Every Web project needs a solid plan to work through the estimate to the site delivery. Here is a list of project questions to plan your Web site with considerations for marketing, design, SEO, unique selling position, E-commerce, and more&#8230;


How would you describe the audience you want to attract?
Do you want the design to reflect your organization or your audience?
What is the primary message you wish to convey to your audience with this project?
What are the secondary objectives you hope to achieve?
Use three adjectives to describe how the overall design should be perceived by the end user. (Examples: conservative, progressive, friendly, formal, casual, serious, energetic, humorous, professional, fun.)
Would you like to see a group of stock photos? If yes, provide a range of the number of final photos that you estimate will be necessary to represent your product or company (e.g. 6 to 12 final photos).
Would it help to see 2-3 design comps? (different color schemes and text treatments)
Is there a color scheme, logo use, and/or photo(s) that you indent to use? (Do you already use marketing materials that should be followed for this project?)
What is the background, product line, and/or mission of your business? (This will help communicate the heart of the company to your audience.)
Please list URLs (web site addresses) of your competitors. Next to each specify what you like and don&#8217;t like about these sites.
Please list any other URLs of sites that have look and feel and layout aspects you would like to emulate on your site.
Please give a range of the number of pages or screens that you feel will be sufficient to meet your project objectives (e.g. 20 to 25 final pages/screens).
For E-commerce Projects:

Please estimate the total number of products (SKUs) and product categories.
Do you have a merchant account with an online payment gateway (e.g. PayPal)?
Would you like to use flat rate for shipping fees or live quotes from shipping providers?


Have you established a budget for the web site?
Do you have a copywriter for the content of your upcoming Web site? Do you need legal counsel to prepare &#8216;terms of use&#8217; and &#8216;privacy policy&#8217; pages?
Do you feel that Flash animation will help your visitors &#8216;catch&#8217; your marketing message? if so, how many concepts/animations do you think will get the message across?
Are you interested in a dynamic or static web site? Dynamic sites use a database to update/edit content and/or product listings via your web browser. Static sites can be packaged with pre-paid maintenance plan for updates/edits.
Do you plan on advertising your products/service online?  (Pay-per-click and banner ads, e.g. Google AdWords)
Do you have a strategy for Search Engine Optimization (SEO) for &#8216;free leads&#8217; and/or Search Engine Marketing (SEM) for maximizing online advertising? SEO includes keyword research and planning your content for performance in Search Engine Results Pages (SERPs)
Finally, and perhaps most important, what is your &#8216;unique selling proposition&#8217;? (i.e. How will you compete in the marketplace? What does your prospect need to know about the advantage of your products/services in order to become a client?)
</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Design, Marketing, Search</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bill Heaton</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Your Web Project, Marketing Strategy Mash Up</title>
		<link>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/your-web-project-marketing-strategy-mash-up</link>
		<comments>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/your-web-project-marketing-strategy-mash-up#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 21:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bill Heaton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engine optimization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web standards]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pixelhandler.dev/?p=6</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Pixel Handler Episode 2, Your Web Project, features web project elements and how they mash up with your marketing strategy. Questions addressed: How do the following mash up to produce results&#8230; design, development, search engine optimization, Web standards, current trends, Web analytics, content, SERPs, usability, marketing strategy, and goal conversions? And, why does it matter? So, what can I do about it? Wrap up: Keep the main thing the main thing! If your unique selling position is  <a class="more" href="https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/your-web-project-marketing-strategy-mash-up">
	&#187;&#160;Read&#160;more&#160;&#8230;</a>]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/your-web-project-marketing-strategy-mash-up/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="https://pixelhandler.dev/podpress_trac/feed/6/0/yourwebproject-pixelhandler-002.mp3" length="13246719" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:17:29</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>pixelhandler.dev – Episode 2 – Your Web Project</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Pixel Handler Episode 2, Your Web Project, features web project elements and how they mash up with your marketing strategy. Questions addressed:

How do the following mash up to produce results&#8230; design, development, search engine optimization, Web standards, current trends, Web analytics, content, SERPs, usability, marketing strategy, and goal conversions?
And, why does it matter?
So, what can I do about it?

Wrap up: Keep the main thing the main thing! If your unique selling position is intimately related to your passion then it will be easy to communicate your message to your target audience.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Design, Marketing, Search</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bill Heaton</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Commentary from PodCamp SoCal, event in Ontario, CA</title>
		<link>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/commentary-from-podcamp-socal-event-in-ontario-ca</link>
		<comments>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/commentary-from-podcamp-socal-event-in-ontario-ca#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2007 01:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bill Heaton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PodCamp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoCal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://398144836</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Chris Brogan, co-founder of PodCamp, a free unconference that explores the benefits and uses of new media community tools. This clip was recorded live at PodCampSoCal for commentary on pixelhandler.dev]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>https://pixelhandler.dev/marketing/commentary-from-podcamp-socal-event-in-ontario-ca/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="https://pixelhandler.dev/podpress_trac/feed/4/0/Pixelhandler001-PodCampSoCal-07.mp3" length="4080535" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:05:42</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Chris Brogan, co-founder of PodCamp, a free unconference that explores the benefits and uses of new media community tools. This clip was recorded live at PodCampSoCal for commentary on pixelhandler.dev</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Chris Brogan, co-founder of PodCamp, a free unconference that explores the benefits and uses of new media community tools. This clip was recorded live at PodCampSoCal for commentary on pixelhandler.dev</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Marketing</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bill Heaton</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
